索唱
水 形 物 語
關於她的故事
If I spoke about it.
如果要講的話
If I did.
我要怎麼說呢
What would I tell you?
我在想
I wonder.
故事發生在什麼時候呢？
Would I tell you about the time?
似乎 發生在很久以前了
It happened a long time ago- It seems...
那位王子當政的最後幾天
In the last days of a fair Prince's reign...
我們還是先來講講那個地方吧
Or would I tell you about the place?
那是一座小城 靠近海岸
A small city near the coast
與世隔絕
but far from everything else...
還能給你講點什麼呢
Or, I don't know.
要麼跟你講講她的故事吧
Would I tell you about her?
公主無法說話
The princess without voice
或許我該提醒你
Or perhaps I would just warn you
這些故事是真實的
about the truth of these facts
這是一個悲歡離合的故事
and the tale of love and loss
還有那個
and the monster
試圖摧毀一切的惡魔
that tried to destroy it all...
荷達克大人
My Lord Hedak.
你感到煩惱
So, you are troubled.
說出來吧
Tell me.
我
I have...
我有罪
I have sinned.
我觸犯了上帝
I've offended the god.
荷達克大人 我是個罪人
I'm deep in sin, my Lord Hedak.
我自有判斷
Let me judge of that.
我對祭祀儀式 有所懷疑
I've doubted the ceremony of the sacrifice.
警報聲把你吵醒了麼
Did the sirens wake you up?
那個巧克力工廠 著火了
It was a fire. The chocolate factory.
你聞到這味了麼 我的天
You smell that? Oh my...
烤熟的可可
Toasted cocoa.
塞翁失馬 焉知非福
Tragedy and delight-- Hand in hand.
要吃點什麼嗎？
親愛的
Oh dear child.
要是沒你在這照顧我 我就會日漸消瘦了
I'd waste away if you weren't here looking after me.
眾所周知 我可是很耐餓的 看這個
I am the proverbial starving. Watch this.
看著樓梯舞
Bojangles, the stair dance.
這舞蹈挺難學的
That's so hard.
卡格尼就做到了
Cagney did it. Different but beautiful.
太美了
我也想學這舞蹈
I want to do that too.
好呀 準備好了麼
All right. Are you ready?
- 好了 - 來吧
- Yep. - Come on.
艾麗莎
Elisa.
下次你來交房租的時候
Next time you're going to bring the rent,
我想讓你留下來看這部聖經主題的電影
I want you to stay and see the bible movie, huh.
我這...我這有兩張免費電影票
I got... I got two free tickets here.
把你的鄰居查爾斯也帶上 他是個好人
You bring your neighbor Charles. He's a good boy.
或者你要看喜劇片? 現在沒幾個人看電影了
Find a movie in comedy? Nobody's coming to the theater, huh.
謝謝
我會給你提供免費的爆米花和蘇打水的
I can throw you a free popcorn and soda.
哦不 我的天 那裏應該放兩個S啊
Oh no, for God's sake! There's two "S' there.
一個S是Mardi Gras 意思是狂歡節
快點 放兩個S
Come on. Two "S". Mardi Grass. Mardi Grass.
艾麗莎 快來 快點來
Elisa, come on. Come here already!
- 你要學會按時上班啊 - 嘿 你幹什麼呢
- You gotta learn to be on time. - Hey, what you doing?
- 就這麼讓她插隊麼 蠢貨 - 少管閒事
- Look her in, Dummy. - Leave her alone, woman.
我幫她排了隊的
I was keepin' her place.
我會檢舉你們的 我會來找你和這啞巴的麻煩的
I get reported. I come after you and the mute.
你去啊 尤蘭達
You do that, Yolanda.
你去啊
You do that.
我這腳 真是疼死我了
My feet are already killin' me.
我那天晚上走之前 給布魯斯特做了麵包熱狗卷
I made Brewster pigs in the blanket tonight before leavin'.
我的天 他就這麼吃完了
Boy, he just ate 'em up.
沒說謝謝 吃的時候也沒發出聲音
No thank-yous, no yum-yums, not a peep-
冷峻的就像一座墓碑那樣
Man is silent as the grave.
如果放屁聲是他對我的奉承
But if farts were flattery
那他簡直堪比文豪莎士比亞了
Honey, he'd be Shakespeare.
然後我回家 給他做早餐
Then I get home and I make him breakfast.
雞蛋 培根 還有烤麵包片加黃油
Eggs, bacon and buttered toast.
我還要給烤麵包雙面都抹上黃油 艾麗莎 搞得就像他是我兒子一樣
I butter the man's toast, Elisa. Both sides-As if he was a child...
他甚至連一聲謝謝都不會說
And I don't even get a 「Thank You」
你懂的感恩 因為你是受過教育的
You'd be grateful, because you are an educated woman.
但是我家的那位嘛 身上只散發出一種野性的魅力
But my Brewster, all he had gone for him was animal magnetism back in the day
原來還挺吸引我的
And workin' awhile.
我的天
What in the same hell?
露！
Lou!
你們這幫小子介不介意把垃圾都丟到桶裏
You boys mind puttin' the trash in the can?
垃圾就應該丟到該丟的地方去
That's what it's that for.
真是難以置信 垃圾就應該丟到該丟的地方去
Hard to believe, uh? That's what it's that for.
- 好 好 抱歉 澤爾達 - 我不知道他們整天在幹什麼
- Alright. Alright. Sorry Zelda, sorry. - I don't know what they're doin'.
要我說 你們真是搞得一塌糊塗
Makin' a goddamn mess, in what I'd say.
- 澤爾達 別聊天了 - 是 長官
- Zelda, stop the chatting please. - Yes sir.
- 沒有必要說那些話 - 抱歉 弗萊明先生
- There's no call for the blaspheme. - Sorry, Mr. Fleming.
佔用各位一點時間
A moment of your time.
今天有一隊新的研究人員和研究對像要來到我們T-4設施
Today, we are receiving a new team and asset here in T-4.
這位是羅伯特·霍夫斯德勒 從加爾維斯頓調過來
This is Dr. Robert Hoffstetler, from our system facility in Galveston.
我不是想虛張聲勢 誇大其詞什麼的
Now, I don't want to bolster or overstate the matter but uh
這個可能是目前這個設施裏
this may very well be the most sensitive asset
最重要的研究對象了
ever to be housed in this facility
- 旅途如何？- 還行
- How was your trip? - Fine.
- 安保人員在哪？- 請稍後
- Who's security here? - Just one moment please.
- 安保人員在哪？- 歡迎來到T-4設施 長官
Security. Who's security here? - Welcome to T-4, sir.
是 長官 我是弗蘭明 這裏的安保負責人
Yes, sir. I am Flemington, Head of Security...
把閒雜人趕出去
Get them out.
幫我把這圓柱箱推進壓縮機裏
Help me move the cylinder into the compressor!
搬過來 搬過來
Bring it here. Bring it here.
艾麗莎 艾麗莎 快走吧
Elisa! Elisa, come on.
那裏是什麼情況 你看到了麼？
What goes on in this place? Did you see that?
是的 我搞了些裝飾品 看起來怎麼樣
Yes, I'm wearing the hair piece. How's is it look like?
小心車
Careful of the car.
嚴格來說那不是什麼裝飾品 是假髮
It's not a hair piece. It's a toupee.
假髮是不會脫落的 懂了吧
It's eternal, see?
坦塔羅斯：源自希臘神話，喻指能夠看目標卻永遠達不到目標的痛苦
坦塔羅斯難求一死
Tantalus never achieved the escape of death.
樹枝上的果實總是放在他夠不著的地方
There's a fruit on the branches was just always out of his reach.
每次他彎腰喝水的時候溪水裏的水就退了
And the water in the stream receded every time he stooped down to drink.
這就是為什麼我們今天說這些話
And so that's why we say things today like
看那些誘人的餡餅
Look at those tantalizing pies.
謝謝 你會回來的 對吧？
Thank you, ya'll come back, y'heah?
是的 早餐吃餡餅 相信我吧
Yes, pies for breakfast! Just trust me on this.
嘿 各位 歡迎來到迪克西·道格餡餅店
Hey folks, welcome to Dixie Doug's.
我之前在這見過你 對吧？
- I've seen you here before, right?
是的 我其實已經來過好幾次了
- Yes, I've been here a couple of times as a matter of fact.
專點萊姆派吧？
- Partial to key lime pie?
是的 來兩份
- Oh yeah, I am. Two to go.
別糾結啦
Just go with it, please.
額 我就好這口
Uh. I-uh. It's a craving I indulge in.
吃這個雖然對我的身體沒什麼好處 我喜歡的東西都不...
It can't possibly be good for me. Nothing that I like is...
這是很好的餡餅 酸橙味
No, no. It's a mighty fine pie, key lime.
你是鼎鼎有名的迪克西·道格麼？
You would happen to be the famous Dixie Doug himself, huh?
當然不是 餡餅是全國派送的
- Heck, no. Pies are trucked throughout the country.
- 他們管這叫「特許經營」 明白了吧？- 哦
- They call it uh, 「franchising」, see? - Oh.
他們給我們提供攪拌機 掛上他們的招牌 就那個「餡餅小子」 是我們的吉祥物
They give us the spinners, the signage. That there's 「Pie Boy」 our mascot.
我一般不提這些的
I don't talk like that.
- 我從渥太華來的 -不會吧
- I'm from Ottawa. - No.
我完全買下它了
I completely bought it.
「這個餡餅真不錯」
「That's-a-great-a-pie」
那個小個子男人 他是意大利人嗎？
The.. The Little guy. Is he supposed to be Italian?
我猜是的
I guess so.
真聰明
That was very clever.
你們都回來了？
Y'all come back now, y'heah?
「你們都回來了」
「Y'all come back now」
你覺得他說這話是認真的嗎？
Do you think he meant it?
他注意到我了 你聽到了他說的那些
He had noticed me. You heard that.
這個餡餅真噁心
This pie is rather sordid.
不要吐出來 下次去的時候 我們試試其他味道
Don't spit it out. Next time we go, well try different flavor.
待會兒再吃
Save it for later.
上帝啊 換個台吧 我不想看那個台
Dear God, change that awfulness. I do not want to see that.
我不想看那個台
I do not want to see it.
這個台還行 這個台還行
That's better. That's better.
哦 看貝蒂！
Oh. Look at Betty!
年輕貌美
Oh. To be young and beautiful
如果時光可以倒流
If I could go back,
回到我18歲的時候
to when I was eighteen
我什麼都不知道 我會給自己一點建議
I didn't know anything about anything. I'd give myself a bit of advice.
什麼建議
比如說 保護好牙齒 多做點愛
I would say. Take better care of your teeth and fuck-a lot more.
真是好建議
That's very good advice.
我漂亮的寶貝
Pretty baby of mine.
看看這個
Will you look at this?
看看
Look.
這裏有我們國家最聰明的一群傢伙 而他們卻在這地板上到處撒尿
Some of the best minds in our country peeing all over the floor in this here facility.
嗯
Mh-mh-mhm.
連天花板上都是尿漬！
There's pee freckles on the ceiling!
他們怎麼撒上去的？
How do they get it up there?
你估計 他們下面那玩意得有多大啊？
Just how big a target do they need, you figure?
他們已經做了充足的練習 這是肯定的
They get enough practice that's for sure.
我的布魯斯特
My Brewster,
可沒人覺得他聰明
no one ever called him a great mind,
但是
but...
就算他 他都有百分之七十的幾率尿進小便池
even he... Man he just hits the can seventy percent of the time.
- 抱歉 先生 - 不不不 沒事 你們繼續打掃
- Excuse us, sir. - No, no, no. That's alright. Go ahead.
你們女士們好像聊得很開心
You ladies seem to be chatting enjoyably.
女士們總能聊得這麼熱火朝天
Girl talk no doubt.
不必介意我
Don't mind me.
艾麗莎
Elisa...
不要碰它
Look, don't touch.
那個可愛的玩意是阿拉巴馬產的
That lovely dingus right there is an Alabama Howdy-do
模制握柄 低電流 高電壓 用來電擊牛的
Molded grip handle. Low-current, High-voltage electric shock cattle prod.
我叫斯特裏克蘭 是安保人員
Name's Strickland, Security.
弗萊明的手下啊
Fleming's security.
不不 男士一般是便前或是便後洗手
Oh no, no. A man washes his hands before or after tending to his needs.
那這很能說明這個男人的特點
That tells you a lot about that man.
如果便前和便後都洗
If he does it both times,
說明他性格軟弱
Points to a weakness in character.
女士們
Ladies
和你們倆聊天非常開心
It was very pleasant chatting with you both.
矮個子的人很刻薄
Short people are mean.
我從來沒有遇到過哪個矮個子的好男人
I've never met a short man that stays nice all the way through.
他們都是暗箭傷人的小人
No, sir, mean little backstabbers, all of 'em.
也許地下缺氧還是什麼的
Maybe it's the air down there, not enough oxygen or somethin.
救命！他在流血！
Help! He's losing blood!
- 救命！- 快來 快來
- Help! - Come on. Come on.
你覺得俄國佬闖進來了麼？ 我可不這樣認為
You think the Russians broke in? I don't think so.
如果他們真的闖進來了 杜安的手下會把他們都殺了 親愛的
And If they did, Duane's meatloaf will kill them all, honey.
有兩聲槍響 你聽見了嗎？
It was two shots, you hear 'em?
其實是三聲 還有尖叫
Alright three, and that scream.
這裏究竟發生了什麼啊？
Whatever happens in this place?
你們兩個 跟我來
You two. Come with me.
現在就去麼 弗萊明先生？ 能讓我們先吃完飯嗎？
Right now, Mr. Fleming, sir? Any chance we might conclude our dinner?
- 現在就來！- 哦
- Now! - Ugh.
天哪 我們遇到麻煩了 我們遇到麻煩了
Oh heavens to Betsy. We're in a pickle. We're in such a pickle.
只給你們20分鐘
You will have exactly twenty minutes,
把實驗室給我徹底打掃乾淨
to render this-this lab immaculate and so on and so forth.
20分鐘
Twenty minutes.
好多血
It's a lot of blood.
屎尿什麼的 我打掃起來沒問題
I can handle piss, I can handle poop...
但是血？ 我怕血
But blood? Mmm. Blood is just something to me.
拿去 幫我擦乾淨
Here Hon, help me mop it up.
我們越快離開這裏越好
The sooner we get out of here the better.
哦！
Oh!
是手指！
It's a finger!
兩隻手指！
It's two fingers!
好 好 把它們拿走 在這等著
Okay, okay. Put 'em away and just wait here.
我去叫弗萊明過來
I'm gonna get this to Fleming.
殘肢在哪兒？
Where are these body parts?
殘肢？
The body parts?
我相信你 親愛的 但是你確定它是活的？
No, I believe you, honey. Are you sure you it was alive?
因為我曾經在馬戲團看到過一隻美人魚
Because I saw a mermaid once in a carnival tent.
結果只是一隻猴子加了條魚尾巴而已 當時真唬住我了
And it was a monkey sewn to the tail of a fish. Looked real to me.
我確定
好吧 我道歉
Alright, I apologized.
我趕時間
I have a deadline
你知道嗎...
You know uh...
玉米片這種零食原本是用來防止手淫的
Corn Flakes were invented to prevent masturbation.
並不奏效
It didn't work.
哦 艾麗絲·費伊的節目開始了...
Oh, Alice Faye just started...
她是個大明星 巨星
She was a huge star, huge.
有一天她終於忍受不了圈子裏的那些屁事兒和潛規則
And one day she couldn't take the bullshit, the backstabbing anymore
就頭也不回地離開了那個圈子
and she just walked away from everything.
當垃圾來看的話 還算不錯 是吧？
Ta-da! It's not bad, is it? For being shit?
它不是垃圾
聽著 你吃完 就上床睡覺
Huh, listen. You eat, you go to bed, you rest.
等我拿到報酬後...
And when I get paid...
我們去吃派！不對 不是我們吃派
We get pie! No, we don't get pie.
我不要
是我吃派 你吃你想吃的
I get pie. You get whatever you want.
祝我好運
Wish me luck.
祝你好運
♫ 你不知道 我有多麼 ♫
You'll never know just how much
♫ 想念你...♫
I miss you...
♫ 你不知道 我有多麼 ♫
You'll never know just how much
♫ 在乎你...♫
I care...
綠色
Green.
- 他們現在想要綠色的果凍 - 但他們之前告訴我要紅色
- They want the gelatin to be green now. - But I was told red.
新理念 大勢所趨
New concept. That's the future, now.
綠色
Green.
對了 他們還想讓這個家庭看起來更快樂點
Oh. And they want them happier- the family.
更快樂 更快樂？
Happier. Happier?
這位父親看起來像剛發現了傳教士式體位(男上女下)
The Father looks like he just discovered the missionary position
賈爾斯
Giles.
好吧...他們還要怎麼高興?
Well uh... What would they supposed to be happy about?
客戶想要照片 我說服了他們
The client want the photographs. I sold them on this
- 很遺憾 它是件好作品 - 它確實是 不是嗎？
- It's too bad-this is nice work. - It is nice, isn't it?
我覺得它是我最好的作品了
I think it's one of my best.
你撐得住吧？
How are you holding up?
- 在喝酒嗎？ - 不 滴酒不沾
- You drinking? - No, not a drop. No.
你離開克萊恩&桑德斯公司之後找到什麼工作了嗎？
You get any work since you left Klein & Saunders?
你是指我被你辭退之後？
You mean since I was asked to leave by you.
我現在不想談論這個
We're not gonna get into this now.
我想回來 伯尼
I want to come back, Bernie
再說吧
We'll see.
先把這個搞定了！
Now do this!
雞蛋
艾麗莎！
Elisa!
你在那裏面幹什麼呢？
What are you doing in there?
清潔啊
Cleaning, huh?
聽著 親愛的
Listen, honey.
那位「叉著腰尿尿」先生想要見我們兩個
Mr. 「I pee with my hands on my hips」 wants to see us both.
澤爾達·D·富勒
Zelda D. Fuller.
你們倆認識多久了 澤爾達？
How long have you two known each other, Zelda?
差不多十年了 長官
About ten years, Sir.
你沒有兄弟姐妹嗎 澤爾達？
No siblings, Zelda?
沒有 長官...
No sir...
對於你們這類人來說 這並不常見 是嗎?
That's not common, is it? For your people?
我媽媽在生完我之後
My momma died after me.
就去世了
After I was born.
你名字裏的「D」是什麼意思？
What does the 「D」 stand for?
是黛利拉 長官
Delilah, Sir.
來自於聖經
On account of the bible.
黛利拉 她背叛了參孫
Delilah. She betrayed Samson.
在哄他入睡之後 剪去了他的頭髮
Lull him to sleep, cut his hair.
非利士人折磨並羞辱了他
Philistines torture him, humiliate him-
還把他的眼睛挖了出來
Burn his eyes out.
看來我媽媽似乎並沒有仔細讀聖經
I guess my momma didn't read the good book close enough
那你呢？
And you?
艾麗莎·埃斯波西托
Elisa Esposito.
埃斯波西托不是「孤兒」的意思嗎？
Doesn't Esposito means 「Orphan」?
兩位女士都是來自帕特南的可憐孤兒
Our Lady of Sorrows Orphanage in Putnam.
他們在河邊的水裏找到了她
They found her by the river in the water.
是你...找到了我的手指？
It was you... that found my fingers?
噢！謝謝
Oh! Thanks.
三個小時的手術
Three hours in surgery.
他們重塑了第一指節 縫合了肌腱
They rebuilt the first phalanx, here, sutured the tendons.
也不知道是否能癒合
Don't know if it's going to take it or not.
上面還沾上了點兒芥末
There was mustard on them.
- 用一個紙袋子裝？ - 當時只有這個能用了 長官
- A paper bag？ - It was all we had, Sir.
鑒於她不能說話 大部分都是我來回答
I answer mostly, on account that she can't talk.
她不能說話？她是聾子嗎？
She can't? Is she deaf?
是啞巴 長官
Mute, sir.
她說她能聽到你
She said she can hear you.
你脖子上的那些傷疤
All those scars on your neck.
原來是傷到了你的聲帶 對嗎？
That's what that it cut your voice box, right?
她說從她還是嬰兒的時候就是啞巴了
She said since she was a baby.
誰會那樣對待一個嬰兒？
Who would do that to a baby?
這個世界充滿了罪惡 不是嗎 黛利拉？
The world is sinful. Wouldn't you say so, Delilah?
好了 我不廢話了
Well, let me say this upfront.
你們打掃那個實驗室 然後離開
You clean that lab. You get out.
我們保存在那兒的那個東西 是個恥辱
The thing we keep in there, is an affront.
你知道什麼是恥辱嗎 澤爾達？
Do you know what an affront is, Zelda?
令人反感的東西？
Something offensive?
沒錯 告訴你 我把那個...
That's right. And I should know, I've dragged that...
骯髒的東西
...filthy thing
從南美洲的沼澤地裏一路拉到這裏
out of the river muck in South America all the way here
並且路上我們都相處地不怎麼愉快
And along the way we didn't get to like each other much.
現在
Now.
你們可能會認為...那個東西看起來像人
You may think... that thing looks human
用兩條腿站立 對嗎？
Stands on two legs, right?
但是...神 是按照自己的模樣 創造人類的
But... we're created in the Lord's image.
你該不會覺得上帝就是長那樣吧？
You don't think that's what the Lord looks like, do you?
先生 我不知道上帝長什麼樣
I wouldn't know, Sir. What the Lord looks like.
人的樣子 澤爾達 上帝長得像人 像我一樣
Well, human, Zelda. He looks like a human, like me.
或者像你
Or even you.
我覺得可能長得更像我一點
Maybe a little more like me, I guess.
好 就這樣吧
Well, that's all.
霍伊特將軍 感謝您的回電
General Hoyt. Thank you for calling me back, Sir.
- 你好點兒了嗎？- 是的 將軍 好多了
- You feel better? - Oh yes, Sir. Much better.
多虧了止痛藥
Pain pills, is all.
- 你被弄斷了兩根手指頭 是這樣嗎？ - 沒錯 兩根手指頭
- You lost two fingers. You wasn't? - Two fingers yeah. He got two fingers.
但是我的大拇指 食指 中指都還健在
But I still got my thumb, my trigger and my pussy finger
聽起來你應該沒事了 - 是的 將軍
Sounds to me like you'll be all right. - Yes, sir, that's right.
期待您日後大駕光臨 將軍
Looking forward to your visit, Sir.
項目的事還需要您來作決策
Decisions need to be made about the asset.
雞蛋
...位於樸次茅斯市中心地段
...free to locations on Downtown Portermouth.
坐擁未來之地
The Future is here.
去休息吧
Get to rest.
9點30來接我
Pick me up on 9:30.
21點30分 知道了 先生
Twenty one hundred and thirty hours. Yes, Sir.
...買不了吃虧買不了上當
...that's great to buy.
我回來了
I'm home.
我給你做了一個煎蛋卷
I made you an omelet!
- 爸爸！告訴你件事情 - 沒有煎餅？
- Hey Dad! Guess what? - No pancakes?
我把家裏的箱子翻了個底朝天 就是找不到平底鍋
I've gone half through the boxes. I can't find the griddle...
- 我就給你做了個奶酪西蘭花煎蛋餅 - 告訴你件事情
- I made you cheese and broccoli omelette, - Guess what?
你怎麼樣了？疼嗎？
How are you feeling? Does it hurt?
- 有一點 止疼藥管點兒用 - 告訴你件事情
- A little bit. Pills help. - Guess what?
- 什麼? - 我們埋了一個時間膠囊 就在新學校那
- What? - We're burying a time capsule, at the new school.
我想問你
I wanted to ask you.
我們未來真的會有噴氣式背包出現嗎？
Do you think we'll all have jet packs, in the future?
- 一定會有的 孩子 - 公交車來了
- Believe it son. - Bus is here.
這裏是美國
This is America.
再見 爸爸！
Bye dad!
趕緊吃完蛋卷 洗完手到樓上來 親愛的
Finish your omelet and wash your hands real good and come upstairs, Sweetie.
我還挺喜歡這裏的
I kinda like it here.
孩子們喜歡草坪 華盛頓離這裏也就半個小時的路程
The kids like the lawn. Plus, DC is just half an hour away, isn't it?
不管怎麼說 這裏是巴爾的摩 伊蓮 沒有人喜歡這裏
It's still Baltimore, Elaine. No one likes Baltimore.
你知道我是怎麼想的嗎？
You know what I'm thinking?
我覺得 我需要一輛新車
I'm thinking. I need a new car.
需要一輛新車是嗎？
Do you need a new car, do you?
凱迪拉克怎麼樣 先生？
How about a Cadillac, Mr.?
理查德
Richard.
噢
Oh.
Oh
噢 理查德！
Oh, Richard!
親愛的 親愛的 親愛的 你的手在流血
Sweetie, sweetie, sweetie. Your hand is bleeding.
安靜 別說話
Silence. Don't talk. I want you in silence.
安靜
Silence.
音樂
你還好吧？
麻雀窩中睡
The sparrow nests on the window sill.
什麼？
What?
麻雀窩中睡
The sparrow nests on the window sill.
魂斷獵鷹喙
And the eagle takes the prey.
什麼？
What?
暗號...
「魂斷獵鷹喙」
走吧
鮑勃！
Bob!
鮑勃!
近來如何
我在這狗屁水泥屋子裏
像個傻子一樣等了你足足一個小時
每次都是在這個爛餐廳接頭！
我會改地兒的
但是你沒有
告訴我們
"鮑勃"
叫我迪米特裏
同志們
我不是"鮑勃"
這是什麼?
迪米特裏
解剖學筆記...
還有...
實驗室結構圖
項目的研究地點
我們從這抽身所需要的一切
都在這了
我會向上級匯報的
我們必須得盡快把這事搞定
米哈爾科夫...
這個生物...
我覺得它能夠
與人交流
交流?
是的 與人交流
我有足夠證據證明
它是種高智商物種
它會識別
它會識別...
語言...
能對音樂作出反應...
你能把這些
也報告給上級嗎？
我會的
現在...
吃吧 迪米特裏
他們把這道菜叫做...
海鮮...
及牛排
海陸大餐
煮好的龍蝦放在這
滋喇滋喇的
但是有點...
過軟了...
還太甜了
艾麗莎！快點！快點！過來
Elisa! Hurry! Hurry! Come on.
快打卡 上帝啊 姑娘
Swipe it. God, girl.
- 你又這樣 澤爾達 - 噢 你老人家歇口氣吧 約蘭達！
- You're doing it again, Zelda. - Oh. Give it a rest, Yolanda!
- 嘿 澤爾達 來一支不 - 吸煙有害健康 杜安
- Hey, Zelda, you want to smoke? - That shit's ain't good for you, Duane.
沒錯 但是一天不抽心發慌
Yeah. But it feel good.
那倒是真的 不是嗎？
It does, doesn't it?
來嘛 艾麗莎 就一支
C'mon Elisa, just one.
來嘛 來嘛 來嘛
C'mon. C'mon. C'mon
別擔心那些攝像頭
Don't worry about that camera.
我們在休息時間都把它挪開了
We push them off on break time.
嗯哼
Uh- mm
這裏是個視角盲點
This here's a blind spot.
我可能要在這裏完成一些事情 請將軍過來 行嗎？
I may have to finish some things in here, fetch the General, will ya?
噢 你想我了？
Oh. You miss me, huh?
我帶了一包水果糖
I took a candy break.
你怕這個啊？
This is what scares you, huh?
那我就用這個吧
Jeez, be used to it by now.
又來了！發出那種炸耳朵的聲音
There you go again. Making that god- awful sound.
是在哭嗎？叫什麼？
Is that you crying, huh? Is that what it is?
你疼麼？啊？
Are you hurting? Huh?
或者說你很憤怒？
Or maybe you're angry?
或者說你還想再咬我一口
Maybe you'd like to get another bite at me.
啊？來啊
Huh? Go ahead.
你還真敢啊
I can't tell.
你在求饒嗎？
Are you begging?
對於我來說 這是我聽過最難聽的噪音
'Cause to me it's just the worst fucking noise I've ever heard.
艾麗莎？
Elisa?
艾麗莎！
Elisa!
霍伊特將軍！歡迎光臨！
General Hoyt! Welcome, Sir!
一切都準備就緒 很榮幸您能來這 將軍！
Everything's ready. Glad to have you here, Sir!
- 見到你很高興 小伙子 - 謝謝
- Good to see you, son. - Thank you.
我的老天 就是這個嗎？
Good God Almighty, Is that it?
比我想像中要大
A lot bigger than I thought.
奇醜無比
Ugly as sin.
你知道嗎 亞馬遜土著把這玩意兒當神來供著
You know, the natives in the Amazon worshipped it as a God.
我倒是真看不出來這是個什麼神
It doesn't look like much of a God now, does it?
嗯 他們是原始人 將軍
Well, they were primitive, Sir. You know they tossed offerings
他們都用些花啊草啊水果什麼的當供品
into the water, flowers, fruits, crap like that.
他們還想用弓箭阻止我們石油開採
Then they tried to stop the oil drill with bows and arrows.
他們的下場可不太妙
That didn't turn out too well.
他在流血 怎麼回事？
He's bleeding. What happened?
怎麼回事？
What happened?
它就是個畜生 霍夫斯德勒 不用管它
It's an animal, Hoffstetler. Just keeping it tame.
「氧氣的滲透作用與二氧化碳的置換」
「Oxygen osmosis and dioxide exchange.」
- 為什麼要抓來這玩意？- 這個物種 長官
- What the hell we got here, Son? - This creature, Sir
可以在兩個獨立的呼吸系統之間轉換
It can alternate between two entirely separate breathing mechanisms.
- 彈塗魚也能做到 - 不
- Mudskipper can do that. - No.
如果你想把人送進太空
Look. You want to put a man in space.
他必須要適應 人類不能適應的各種環境
He's gonna have to endure conditions the human body just wasn't made for.
在我們同蘇聯人的太空競賽中 這能讓我們佔上風
This gives us an edge against the Soviets.
他在空氣中能存活多久?
How long can it breathe outside the water?
事實上 長官 我們並不瞭解這東西
Reality, is, Sir. We don't know jackshit about this thing.
我們都知道 蘇聯人想研究它
Well, the Soviets want it. We know that much.
那些混蛋
Those cockeyed bastards.
他們把狗送進太空 我們可以嘲笑他們
You know, they let them send a dog up in the space and we get a good laugh.
但是緊接著他們 把人也送上去了
Then next thing you know, they send a human up.
一個衛星繞著地球飛 天知道在搞些什麼陰謀詭計
A Ruskie, orbiting our planet, doing God knows what?
現在輪到 赫魯曉夫笑了
Who's laughing now? Krushchev.
他們送狗上了太空 他開心了 接著把一個蘇聯混蛋送上天
That's it. We let him put a dog in space, he laughs, puts a commie in space
他又笑了 然後他向古巴發射了導彈
he laughs, puts missiles in Cuba.
我們啥也沒學到
Have we learned nothing?
長官 我要把它放回水中
Sir. We need to get him back in the water
你看這些科學家 他們就像藝術家 愛上了他們的玩物
See this Scientist, they are like artists. They fall in love with their playthings.
這裏 長官 看這裏
Now, right here-you see? Along the middle?
這個生物有一塊厚實的關節軟骨組織 將主要和次要肺分開了
This creature has a thick jointed cartilage separating the primary and secondary lungs.
我說得對吧 鮑勃?
Am I explaining this correctly, Bob?
- 是的 但是我們必須要... - 光拍X光片是不夠的
- Yes, but we have to... - It makes the X-rays inconclusive.
- 理論上是的 長官 但我們要先... - 如果我們要打敗蘇聯人
- In principle, Sir, yes but... - If we want to get the edge on the Soviets
- 我們應該 解刨這個東西 - 不 不行
- we need to vivisect this thing. - No, no, no.
- 解剖它 從裏到外研究 - 不能這樣
- Take it apart. Learn how it works. - No.
不 不行  那不是我們的初衷
No. That would defeat the purpose
長官 他暈過去了 救救他吧
Sir? He's passed out. Please.
把它放進罐子裏 給他加壓
Put him in the tank. Let him pressurize.
霍伊特將軍
General Hoyt, sir!
在任何情況下 您都不能殺死這個生物
You cannot, under any circumstance, kill this creature.
數數這些星星 小伙子 一共有五個!
Count these with me, Son. There's five of them.
這證明我可以 為所欲為
That means I can do whatever the hell I want.
如果你想聊你的研究 我會聽你說完
You wanna plead your case? I'll listen to it.
但最後.. 是我下決定
But, end of the day, it is my damn decision.
把那該死的玩意剖開
Crack the damn thing open.
仔細研究研究 結束任務了
Lean what you can and close up shot.
好好休息一下 斯特裏克蘭
And give yourself a good pat on the back, Strickland.
- 就這樣吧 - 謝謝 長官
- You've done it. - Thank you sir.
現在快點開始吧 小伙子
Now hurry up and finish this job, son.
馬上開始 長官
Absolutely, sir.
救他出來? 你在想些什麼?
Get him out? What are you talking?
不 絕對不行
No! Absolutely not!
因為這是犯法! 這就是原因
Because it's breaking the law! And that's what.
可能連談論它 都犯法了
We're probably breaking the law, just talking about it.
他很孤獨
非常孤獨
"他很孤獨!" 是麼
Oh, he's alone. Oh.
那我們每次去中餐館吃飯
This mean that... whenever we go to a Chinese restaurant
你都要解救浴缸裏的每條魚麼?
you want to save every fish in the tank?
所以他孤單又怎麼樣呢? 我們都孤單
So what if he's alone? We're all alone.
"它是我見過最孤單的東西"
It's the loneliest thing you've ever seen
好吧 你自己都說了
Well you just said it, right? You just said it.
你說他是個「東西」他是個怪胎
You called it a thing. It's a thing. It's a freak.
念出我的手語
我明白你的意思
I can understand you.
你根本沒在聽
重複一遍
重複
冷靜 我的天 冷靜
Calm down! God, calm down!
念出我的手語
好吧 我重複說一遍
Alright. I will... I will repeat it to you.
「我是什麼?」
"What I am?
我張開嘴巴 和他一樣
I move my mouth, like him.
我發不出任何聲音 和他一樣
I make no sound, like him.
那又如何?
What does that make me?
現在我的一切 和我所經歷的
All that I am, all that I've ever been
都把我 引向他
Brought me here to him.
你用的是「他」 現在改稱"他" 了嗎?
You see, you're saying "him". It's a "him" now.
這...
It's a...
你打到我了!
You just hit me!
艾麗莎 放開我
Elisa, let go of me.
我聽著呢 你從來沒打過我！
I'm looking, I'm looking. You've never... hit me!
"當他看向我的時候 他看著我的方式
When he looks at me, the way he looks at me.
他並不覺得我缺少什麼
He does not know what I lack.
也不會覺得我是不完整的
Or how I am incomplete.
他看到的我 是真實的我
He sees me for what I am, as I am.
他見到我很快樂
He's happy to see me
每天 每次見到他 都是如此
Every time, every day.
現在 我要麼救他
And now I can either save him...
要麼讓他死去 "
...or let him die.
我要走了 我必須離開了
I'm leaving. I have to... no I have to leave.
艾麗莎 住手! 聽我說
Just Elisa, please stop! Listen to me. Just listen to me.
我要走了 我現在必須離開
I have to go! I'm leaving now because this...
艾麗莎 這對我很重要 這是我第二次機會!
Elisa, this is very important to me. This is a second chance for me!
對不起 但我得走
I'm sorry, but I have to go.
當我回來的時候 我們再也不要討論這個了
And when I come back. We will not talk about this, ever again.
艾麗莎... 夠了
Elisa... there's... Alright. Alright.
我們是什麼 你和我算什麼? 我們沒辦法!
What are we? What are you and I? What we are? We are nothing!
我們一點辦法都沒有
Nothing. We can't do nothing!
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
但這...它...
But this-this-this is just...
根本不是人類!
Oh god! He's not even human!
我的天
God.
什麼
What?
如果我們
什麼也不做
那我們也算不上人類
吉爾斯!
Giles!
- 我在等你 - 我知道 對不起
- I've been waiting. - I know, sorry.
沒關係
It's okay.
進去談嗎?
We going in?
你把畫寄過來就好
You should've just mailed the art.
不 我想親自給你和你的團隊看
No! I wanted to show you it to you and the team and person
這是我的傑作
It's some of my best work.
已經不能更綠了！
And this green as can be!
這個...
It's uh...
現在好像不太合適 也許以後再談吧
It's not a good time. Maybe later.
好吧 沒問題
Oh well, sure, no problem.
你什麼時間合適呢 伯尼?
What would be good time for you, Bernie?
這是你畫的嗎？
You painted that?
是啊
Yeah.
哇！你可真棒！
Wow! You're good!
不過沒有照片那樣逼真
Apparently, not as good as a photograph.
但也不錯了 是嗎？
But it's good, isn't it, huh?
反正我畫不出來
Pfft. I couldn't paint like that.
來吧 我請了
Here. On me.
給我的？
For me?
我們這沒有多少你這樣的人 你看起來...
We don't get many like you in here. You seem...
很有教養 我喜歡跟你聊天
very educated. I like talking to you.
事實上...嗯...
The thing is... That's the...
我來這的原因是...
The only reason that I come in here is...
是來聊天的 而且這派味道真不錯 是嗎？
The conversation. And the pie is mighty fine too, isn't it?
嗯 是啊
Yeah. Yeah.
沒加檸檬 但是很美味
It's no key lime. But it's good.
是這樣的 我獨自一人工作
You know, I work alone. And uh...
我最好的朋友不怎麼喜歡聊天
my best friend is not much of a conversationalist.
知道嗎？聊天也是在這工作的一部分
You see? That's part of being on the job here.
比如做個調酒師
It's like being a bartender.
你為客人做餡餅 傾聽他們的故事 慢慢瞭解他們
You serve people pie, you listen to their problems. Get to know them.
我想要更瞭解你
I'd like to get to know you better.
你在幹嘛 老傢伙？
- What the hell are you doing, old man?
噢 抱歉
Whoa. Oh- oh.
嘿！別坐吧檯 把東西打包帶走 你們不能坐這
Hey! No- no- no. Not the counter. Take out only. You can't sit there.
你們想要什麼 就點好 然後打包帶走
You want something, you order, you take it out.
但店裏很空啊 吧檯...
But it's empty... The counter is-
有人預訂了 訂了一整天 你不能在這坐
All reserved. All day. You don't sit down.
歡迎再來啊 聽見了嗎？
Y'all come back now, Y'hear?
你沒必要這樣跟他們說話
You don't need to talk to them like that.
你也該走了
You should go, too.
別再來了 這裏是家庭餐廳
And don't come back. This is a family restaurant.
我找不到其他人聊天了
I have no one.
你是唯一一個能聽我說話的人
And you're the only person that I can talk to.
聽著
Now.
你想要什麼都可以
Whatever this thing is
只要你說需要
You need it.
那麼
So...
你只需要告訴我該怎麼做就行
You just tell me what to do.
- 「所有往事...」 - 「春日已逝」
- "All those things..." - "As the spring recedes..."
走吧
Let's go!
莫斯科方面不會支持你的計劃
為什麼?
風險太大
時間太緊
什麼?！
我們只有兩個選項 迪米特裏
其一...
你想辦法推遲計劃
至少一周
但他們明天就要實施了
所以...
只剩下
第二個選擇
以色列炸彈
你把它安在保險絲盒子上
然後會停電十分鐘
沒有監控 沒有阻礙
然後...
你把這個給它注射
注射
殺了它
毀了它
你還好嗎?
我來到這個國家
盡我所能的學習
既是一個愛國者...
也是科學家
我們還有許多可以學習的
我們不需要學
我們只要讓美國人
沒機會學
凱迪拉克帝威 世界上最好的車
Cadillac DeVille. Best car ever made.
v8發動機 390馬力 乾淨利落得像嶄新的美元大鈔
V8, 390 CID. Clean and crisp like a fresh dollar bill
- 我只是隨便看看 - 我只是隨便說說
- I am just idling around. - And I'm just talking.
收音功能 加載空調 電動車窗 電子助力剎車
AM radio, air conditioning, power windows, power breaks,
電子助力方向盤 電動座椅調節
power steering, power seats
可更換豪華內飾 有143種選擇
All deluxe interior appointment choices. 143 options.
而這輛...
Now this is...
就是個帶輪子的泰姬陵
The Taj- Mahal on wheels.
- 我不太喜歡這綠色 - 這可不是綠色 是水鴨色
- I'm not sure about the green. - Oh, it's not green, my friend, Teal.
- 好吧 水鴨對我來說像綠色 - 但它不是 看 這是限量款
- Well, Teal looks green to me. - But it isn't, see? It's a limited edition.
12層噴漆 手工拋光 所有細節鍍鉻裝飾
Twelve coats of paint. Polished by hand. All authentic chrome detailing.
美國百分之八十的成功男士都駕駛凱迪拉克
Four out of five successful men in America drive a Cadillac.
- 這是真的嗎？ - 這就代表著未來
- Is that a fact? - This here, is the future.
而你就是那駛向未來的人
And you strike me as a man who is headed there.
- 駛向哪？- 怎麼了？未來啊
- Where? - Why? The Future.
你應該擁抱未來 這輛車屬於你
You are the man of the future. You belong in this car.
哦先生 這真是輛漂亮的車
Wow, Sir! That is a beautiful car.
要我說 這車開起來一定感覺很好吧？
What can I say? You gotta feel good drivin' that, eh uh?
這綠色多棒啊
And what a wonderful shade of green, huh?
- 是水鴨色 - 水鴨色
- Teal. - Teal.
早上五點 我開車到裝載台
So at 5 a.m. I drive my car down the loading ramp.
那時正在交班
And the shifts are changing
我有多長時間？5分鐘？我會記住的
How much time do I have? 5 minutes? I'll remember.
5點 5分鐘 五- 五 五- 五
5 a.m., 5 minutes. Five- five. Five- five.
你要去移動攝像頭
You're going to move the cameras.
我們要對一下表 就像電影裏他們那樣
And uh. I'm gonna be synchronizing our watches, just like they do in the movies.
哦天 我真為你驕傲 你竟然一點也不怕
Oh God. I'm so proud of you. God. You're just... You're not afraid.
你怕？很怕？別跟我說這些！我已經嚇死了！
You are? Very? Don't tell me that! I'm terrified.
這是我最好的作品之一
I think this is some of my best work.
邁克爾·帕克 很好 這名字看起來值得信賴 有點男人味
Michael Parker. A good, trustworthy name. A little butch.
年齡 51歲？
Yes, age fifty- one?
54歲？
Fifty- four.
你這是在說我老嗎
It don't have to be rude.
57歲吧
Fifty seven.
我帶上假髮吧 這樣是可行的
I put the hair on, I can pull it off.
我可以穿這件 我應該...
I can wear this. Or I have to uh...
我還有這件 這件好像在說「有工作的男人」
Or I have this. This I think this one says 「Working Man」.
還有這件 這件奶油糖色的假領帶 有點隨意又有點時髦
Now this. This says with butterscotch "tie「 it says casual but with stylish」.
你喜歡這件？我同意 我覺得我們準備好了
So, you like this? I agree. I agree. I think we're ready.
斯特裏克蘭先生
Mr. Strickland!
莎莉 你能叫埃斯波西托小姐來打掃一下撒掉的水嗎
Sally, could you call Mrs. Esposito to clean up this spill?
知道嗎 我自己想不明白 你並沒什麼好看的
You know, I can't figure it out myself. You're not much to look at.
但想想看 我一直在想著你
Go figure. I keep thinking about you.
你說你是啞巴 你是完全不能出聲
When you say you're mute, are you entirely silent
還是能咿呀點聲響？
Or do you squawk a little?
有些啞巴能出聲 不怎麼好聽
Some of you squawk. Not pretty.
我只是想讓你知道 我不怕傷疤
I just want you to know. I do not care about the scars.
我不在意那些傷疤
I don't mind those scars.
我也不在乎你不會講話
I don't mind that you can't speak, either.
你在我面前跪下的時候
When you come right down to it
我喜歡這樣
I like it.
很喜歡
A lot.
有點挑起我的慾望了
Kind of gets me going.
我敢肯定我會讓你叫出聲來
I bet I can make you squawk a little.
嘿 親愛的 你還好嗎？
Hey, honey, are you okay?
你快點收拾 我想早點回家
You hurry up. I want to be home early.
我的腳痛死了
My feet are killin' me.
我們必須延遲計劃
We need to delay the procedure.
進我的辦公室要敲門
Knock before you enter my office.
這很緊急！
This is urgent!
書名：《積極思考出奇效》
出去 敲門我才讓你進來 然後再談事情
Go back out. Knock. Then I'll let you in and we'll talk.
這是規矩 按規矩行事
That's the protocol. Follow the protocol.
進來吧
Come in.
幫我把門關一下好嗎？
Will you get the door for me, please?
看見了嗎？這就對了嘛 現在我們可以談事情了
See? That is the way. Now we talk.
我還需要時間
I need more time.
不要讓你的挫敗感
Don't let the fact that you feel like a loser now
- 和你的求勝心切影響到... - 我沒有求勝心切！
- that your competitive tendencies... - I'm not competitive!
我不想毀滅這麼複雜且美麗的生物
I don't want an intricate, beautiful thing destroyed.
這個東西死了之後 你學到了東西 我也會離開這裏
This thing dies. You learn. I leave. Out of here.
和我的家人一起 在某個安靜美麗的城市安定下來
Settle down. My family settles down. Somewhere. Nice. A real city.
這種生物非常聰明 具備語言能力
This creature is intelligent. Capable of language,
能理解情感
of understanding emotions.
蘇聯人 亞洲佬不也是這樣麼
So are the Soviets, the Gooks
我們照樣殺了他們 不是麼？
And we still kill them, don't we?
關鍵是 這裏不是動物園
The bottom line is, this is not a petting zoo.
而且我再也不想在這個鬼地方多呆一秒了
And I don't want to be in this shithole any longer than I need.
你想嗎？
Do you?
鮑勃！你想嗎？
Bob! Do you?
不 我不想
No, I don't.
嘿 你還在等什麼？
Hey, what are you waiting for?
- 你看見艾麗莎了嗎？- 快點 澤爾達！
- Have you seen Elisa? - Come on, Zelda!
你是不是在攝像頭上動了手腳？在裝貨碼頭上？
Did you move the camera? On the loading dock?
你是要把他帶到那去嗎？帶他經過服務隧道？
Is that where you are taking him? Through the service tunnels?
真是聰明啊
That's very smart.
誰在背後指使你的？
Who do you work for?
水的含鹽量必須保持在5%到8%
Water must be kept at 5 to 8 percent salinity.
食鹽就可以
Table salt will do.
把這個加入水中 三天一次
Mixed one of these in this water. Every three days.
粗蛋白也是必需成分
Raw protein diet is a must.
五分鐘之後 我在裝貨碼頭和你會合
In five minutes, I'll meet you at the loading dock.
燈會熄滅 所以做好心理準備
The lights will go out, so be prepared.
斯特裏克蘭先生 距離活體解剖還有12小時 而且...
Mr. Strickland, Sir. 12 hours to the vivisection of asset. And uh...
請在這裏簽名
I need your signature here, please.
停車 不要動
Hold it, right there.
- 邁克爾 帕克 是你本人嗎？ - 是的
- Michael Parker. Is that you? - My whole life.
你瘋了嗎？
Are you out of your mind?
不要這樣做 艾麗莎！別這麼做！
Do not do this, Elisa! Don't do this!
- 那是什麼？是什麼工具車？- 是洗衣工嗎？
- What's that? What's that vehicle? - Laundry man?
但是沒有登記過！
But it is not scheduled!
- 長官！- 和我在裝貨碼頭會合
- Sir! - Meet me at the loading dock.
- 長官！你要干... - 去找支援
- Sir! What do you... - Get back up.
- 先生請下車 - 哦天哪我不擅長處理這種情況
- Step out of the vehicle, Sir. - Oh God, I'm not good at this.
下車 快！別讓我再重複一遍
Out of the vehicle. Now! I will not say it again.
- 請別向我開槍 - 下車！
- Please don't shoot me. - Get out!
你們還在等什麼？我們快沒時間了
What are you waiting for? We're out of time!
現在下車！
Get out now!
必須要走了！快點！
We have to go! Hurry!
哦！我們要下地獄了！
Oh! Woman we gon' burn in hell!
快點 快推！推！
Come on, push! Push!
我發誓我不是故意不下車的 我一直不會弄機械的這些東西...
I swear, I'm not doing this on purpose! Mechanical objects and I don't get along...
她在碼頭等你！
She's waiting for you at the dock!
- 快走！- 好的 馬上
- Go! Now! - Okay. Hold on.
那個男人是誰？他剛才好像殺人了
Who's that man? I think he just killed someone!
哦我的天哪！我的天哪！我的天哪！
Oh my God! Oh my God! Oh my God! Oh my God!
準備好了嗎？準備好了嗎？
Are we ready? Are we ready?
他真是美啊
He's so beautiful!
是我撞的嗎？
Did I do that?
我真的不擅長這個
I'm just not good at this.
快走！快走！
Move! Move!
不！
No!
鹽？你在說什麼？鹽？
Salt? What are you talking about, Salt?
艾麗莎！
Elisa!
以色列「炸彈」
Israeli 「Popper.」
你聞到鎂的味道了嗎？
Do you smell the magnesium?
俄國人恨死猶太人了 但還是用他們做的這些小玩意
The Russians hate the Jews, but they can't get enough of their gadgets
他們怎麼進去的？
How did they get in?
偽造的身份證件 假牌照等等之類的
Forged ID. Fake plates. And so on and so forth...
他們還動了碼頭上的主攝像頭 先生
And they moved the main video camera on the dock, Sir.
好吧 沒必要告訴別人 我還有24小時來解決這件事
Well, no one has to know. We got 24 hours before I bounce out.
我已經上報了
I called it in?
你上報了？
Did you called it in?
剛出事的時候我就
The moment it happened, I...
斯特裏克蘭先生
Mr. Strickland, Sir.
怎麼了
What is it, Sally?
長官 霍伊特將軍在等您的電話
Sir, General Hoyt is on the phone.
那個兩棲人對我們來說就像太空狗一樣珍貴 斯特裏克蘭
That thing was our Space Dog, Strickland.
你知道的
You know that.
先生 我會把他抓回來的
Sir, I'm gettin' it back.
我沒有-我不能再往壞處想了 先生
I don't-I can't be in a negative frame of mind, Sir.
所以你感覺很好麼？
So you're feeling good?
我有信心 把他抓回來
Feeling strong. Getting it back
你能搞定的 必須把它抓回來 為了我 你能辦到的下伙子
You can get it done. You're gonna get it done. For me, Son. For me.
你計劃那天放他走嗎？
Is that when you're planning on releasing him?
十號？
On the tenth?
如果降雨推遲了呢？
So what if the rains are late?
水道會怎麼樣？
What happens with the canal?
會下雨的
好吧
All right.
那是什麼？
What's that?
讓我看看
Let me see it.
那是給我的嗎？
Is that for me?
這很好 你繼續保持
That's good, keep it up.
看起來你還什麼都不知道呢
Lookin' like you don't know anything.
如果他們來找我的麻煩了 請上帝保佑我
Lord help me if they ask me if I do.
我不太會撒謊
I am not a good liar.
對布魯斯特除外
Except for Brewster.
為了維持婚姻我撒了很多謊
Takes a lot of lies to keep a marriage going.
所有人員請注意
All personnel.
請準備好你們的身份證和門禁卡
Prepare to present your ID and entrance card.
保密措施已經...
Security measures has been...
這是怎麼了？
What in the...?
全體人員請注意
Attention. All personnel.
請準備好你們的身份證和門禁卡
Prepare to present your ID and entrance card
你讓我們惹上大麻煩了！
You got us in trouble!
在我看來 我們面對的一個受過高度訓練的組織 先生
In my opinion, we are looking at a highly trained group, Sir.
長官 我覺得是特種部隊之類的
I'm thinking, conceivably, Sir. Special Forces and so on and so forth.
蘇軍特種部隊？
Red Army Special forces?
八九不離十
Conceivably.
一個受過高度訓練 經費充足的精英組織
A highly-trained, well-financed, elite group.
高效率 殘忍的 工作極其精準
Highly efficient, ruthless, clockwork precision.
潛入行動不到五分鐘就結束了 先生
Infiltration took less than five minutes, Sir.
我怎麼都覺得要花上十分鐘才能完成行動吧
I can sure the estimate of this Strict Force of at least 10 minutes.
你一直是一個人呆著嗎？
Have you always been alone?
你有過朋友嗎？
Did you ever have someone?
你知道你發生了什麼嗎？你知道嗎？
Do you know what happened to you? Do you?
因為我不知道 我不知道我身上發生了什麼
'Cause I don't. I don't know what happen to me.
我不知道
I don't know.
我照鏡子 唯一能認出的就是那雙眼睛了
I look in the mirror, the only thing that I recognize are these eyes.
長在一個老男人的臉上
In this old man's face.
有時我覺得我生的太早 有時又覺得生的太晚了
And sometimes I think I was either both too early or too late for my life.
可能我們倆都是老古董吧
Maybe we're both just relics.
先生 我找到他們了
Sir? I got them.
澤爾達 艾麗莎 請進
Zelda, Elisa. Come in.
看來在事情發生之前 你們倆已經打卡下班了
Looks like you two, punched out before the incident.
所以
So.
如果你們知道關於一些洩露物的信息
If you know something about what transpired here.
你們有義務去報告所有的細節
It's your obligation to report any detail.
無論這些細節多麼的微不足道
No matter how small or trivial it may seem.
「微不足道」的意思是「不重要」
"Trivial" means "unimportant".
我沒發現有什麼反常的 沒有
I didn't seem nothin' out of the ordinary. No.
微不足道的也沒有 你看 我的腳傷了
Or trivial. See? My feet were hurting...
那你呢？
What about you?
她什麼都沒看到
She didn't see anything.
霍夫斯德勒  霍夫斯德勒博士
Hoffstetler. Dr. Hoffstetler.
你看到他進出過這個實驗室嗎？
Did either of you see him coming in or out of the lab?
他在這兒工作 不是嗎？
He works there, doesn't he?
我說的是另一個意思
I mean in a different way.
做一些不尋常的事情
Doing something different.
你是說微不足道的那種事麼 沒有 先生
Something trivial? No sir.
我在這兒幹什麼？
What am I doing?
我居然詢問你們這些傢伙
Interviewing the fucking help...
洗衣服的
The shit cleaners...
掃廁所的
The piss wipers.
你們兩個走吧 離開這兒
You two, go ahead. Leave.
你跟我說什麼？
What did you say to me?
- 她說什麼？-我不知道
- What did she say? - I didn't catch it.
- 他說什麼？- 她說「謝謝你」
- What is she saying?! - She is saying "Thank you".
下一個
Next.
我們要做的只有一件事了
There's only one thing left to do.
「志願者」
"Volunteer".
不要！不要！
No! No!
我想早點回家
I want to get home early.
最近布魯斯特很愛生氣...
Brewster has been in a bad mood lately...
聖主耶穌！
Holy Jesus!
你躲在女士更衣室幹什麼？
What are you doing standing in the shadows of the women's locker room??
他們可能一直在看著我 這兒應該沒有攝像機
They may be watching me, and there are no cameras here/
理由不錯嘛
For good reason.
你在這個時候見我們是有何貴幹？
What if you caught us in an inconvenient moment?
- 我需要知道他是否安好 - 它很好
- I need to know that he is alright. - He is.
- 什麼時候放它走？ - 會盡快的
- When will you release him? - Soon.
當雨水將連接大海的水道填滿的時候
When the rain fills the canal that flows to the sea.
如果你需要任何幫助
If you need anything.
放了它 趕緊的
Release him. Soon.
她說什麼？
What did she say?
她說 「你是個好人」霍夫斯德勒博士
She said, you're a good man, Doctor Hoffstetler.
我叫德米特裏
My name is Dimitri.
很高興認識你
Honored to meet you.
嗨 啞巴！有你的電話！
Hey, dummy! Phone call for you.
很緊急
It's urgent.
不用擔心我 我很好 相信我 我沒事
Don't worry about me. I'm fine. Believe me, I'm fine.
你受傷了 你流血了
它跑了 這不是他的錯
He ate Pandora, it wasn't his fault.
他是一個野生動物
He's a wild creature.
我們不能要求它做其他任何事情
We can't ask him to be anything else.
艾莉莎 去找他 快去！
Elisa, Go find him. Go. Go!
快去！
Go!
你很幸運
You're lucky.
我一直在努力保持清醒
I stayed awake as long as I could
但畢竟我不是年輕人了
But I'm not even a young man anymore.
他還好麼？你確定麼？
Is he alright? You sure?
你要去哪兒？ 別 別
Where are you going? No, no.
好的 別別 別和小貓呆在一起
Ok. No, no. Don't play with the kitties.
別跟它們在一起玩
Don't play with the kitties.
我不生氣
I'm not angry.
你確實這麼做了 沒關係 我覺得這不衛生
You did that. That's okay. Ooh. I don't think that's sanitary.
可以了
Enough.
有趣的傢伙
Interesting guy.
全體人員請注意
All personnel.
請準備好你們的身份證和門禁卡
Prepare to present your ID and entrance card.
你找我？
You wanted to see me?
那個調查進行得怎麼樣了？
How's it going? The investigation?
噢 進展不錯
Well, we have a promising lead.
是麼？
Really?
那挺好的
That's good to hear.
你從加爾維斯頓調過來
You joined us in Galveston.
- 但你之前在哪裏工作呢 霍夫斯德勒？- 博士
- But where were you before, Hoffstetler? - Doctor.
- 什麼？- 請叫我
- Excuse me? - Doctor.
霍夫斯德勒博士
Hoffstetler.
這是規矩
Protocol.
- 我之前在威斯康星大學麥迪遜分校 - 那就對了
- Wisconsin. Madison. - That's right.
你放棄了終身教職 對吧？
You gave up a tenure track position. Didn't you?
為了我們
Gave it all up...
什麼都不要了
For us.
那麼 我想你現在已經準備好離開我們了 對嗎？
I suppose you're getting ready to leave us now, then, huh?
如果找不到那個生物的話 是的
Only if the creature isn't found.
你想什麼呢？ 你真以為我們能找到它？
What do you think? You think we will find it?
噢 你說過你們有進展了
Well, you said you had a lead.
確實
I do.
親愛的 你在傻笑什麼？
Why you smiling, hon?
別這副表情好嘛
Stop looking like that.
你倆幹嘛啦？
What happened?
怎麼可能？
Why?
他？
How?
他怎麼做到的？
他他他他有那東西？
Does he? Have a?
這樣
Mmm.
再這樣打開 就長出來了嘛
永遠別以為男人很單純
Never trust a man.
即使他那裏光禿禿空蕩蕩平平無奇
Even when he looks flat down there.
請進
你的撤離文件...
他們快準備好了
首先 我有個問題
是嗎? 請問吧
你們想來點...
黃油蛋糕嗎?
好的 謝謝
你注射了...
那個研究對像之後
你怎麼處理屍體的?
我很好奇
我進行瞭解剖
沒什麼價值
列寧曾經說過
死魚是沒有價值的
列寧
說過這個?
蛋糕不錯！
你有牛奶嗎?
也許...
也許是...
你記錯了
等我們的回信
不會很久的
我剛報名參加了一個人類學課程
I just signed up in anthropology.
我們全班都要去亞馬遜雨林
We're gonna go have classes in the Amazon Jungle...
- 在南美洲 - 南美洲？
- in South America. - South America?
哦天哪 那可得大清早就出發
Oh man. You have to get off early in the morning
那地方很遠的
That's a long hike.
- 我們要待在那兒 - 我們？
- We're gonna stay down there. - We are?
哦 不 你該不會也要去吧
Oh no. You're not coming along too.
嘗嘗這個吉利丁凍糕
This is a gelatin parfait.
你會愛上這個味道的
You will love it.
《伯南扎的牛仔》：1959年首播，是美國第一部彩色西部連續劇
爸爸 我們能看《伯南扎的牛仔》嗎？
Dad, can we watch Bonanza?
那對你們來說太暴力了 你知道我今天在想什麼嗎？
Bonanza is much too violent. You know what I was thinking today?
我們帶著孩子
We get the kids a P-U-P-P...
怎麼回事？ 這水都涌進我的電影院啦
What is going on? I've got water pouring into my theater.
有四個付了錢的觀眾 我還得給他們退票
I have four paying customers. I can't afford a refund.
可能是某個管道的問題 我會處理的
It's probably a pipe. I'll take care of it.
- 修不好就別住這裏了 - 我會修好的
- If you don't fix it. No more renting. - I will fix it.
艾麗莎！
Elisa!
我的天哪！
Dear God!
艾麗莎！
Elisa!
我在擦乾我的頭髮
I'm toweling my hair.
我的頭髮！
It's my hair!
還有 看看我的手臂 那些傷口
And... and... look at the arm. The wound.
好像從來沒有過一樣 太神奇了
As if it was never there. Look at them.
你說過 人們把他當成神一樣供奉著
You said... He was worshipped like a god.
他是上帝嗎？ 我不這麼覺得 他可是吃了一隻貓
Is he a God? I don't look to him as a God. He ate a cat
哎 我真不知道
So I-I don't know! I don't know!
我們得讓他多留一陣子
We have to keep him around, awhile
就一陣子
A little while.
喂？
Hello?
撤離...
已經安排好了
老地方
四十八小時之後
四十八小時?
四十八小時
你的水 長官
Your water, Sir.
- 還有 長官 霍伊特將軍找你 - 不 別接通
- And, Sir, General Hoyt. - Uh-mm. Uh-mm.
告訴他我不在 我會打給他 總之別接進來
Tell him I'm not in, tell him I will call him back. Don't put him through.
不是來電 長官 他已經在你辦公室裏了
No, Sir. He's in your office.
現在我們唯一關心的就是那個研究對像
At this point our only concern is the asset.
你找到它了嗎？
Do you have it?
還在找 長官
Still in the wind, sir.
那可不好
That won't do.
嗯 我知道
Yes sir. I know.
你認識我多久了 長官？
You've know me for how long, Sir?
- 十三年了 釜山戰役就認識了 - 是的 長官
- Thirteen years. Battle of Pusan. - Yes, sir.
一個男人盡其一生都是有信仰 忠誠 做事高效的
A man is faithful, loyal, efficient all of his life. All of it
還很有能力
And he is... useful.
而他期望...
And he expects...
他當然想要一定的回報
He has certain expectations in return.
但是 他失敗了
And then... He fails.
一次 僅此一次
Once. Only once.
那會導致什麼？
What does that make?
會讓他變成失敗者嗎？
Does that make him a failure?
當一個男人完成任務 來證明他自己 將軍
When is a man done, Sir? Proving himself?
他是一個好人
A good man.
一個體面的人
A decent man.
體面？
Decent?
一個體面的人不會把事情搞砸
A man must have the decency not to fuck up.
這是一種體面
That's one thing.
真正的體面
That is real decent of him.
另一種體面嘛 其實並不重要
The other kind of decency. It doesn't really matter.
我們摒棄它 不是因為我們沒有這種品質
We sell it. But it's an export.
而是因為它對我們沒用
We sell it 'cause we don't use it.
36小時以後 這一切就結束了
36 hours from now, this entire episode will be over.
你也一樣會完蛋
And so will you.
我們的世界將會出現一個破洞
Our universe will have a hole in it with your outline.
你會去另一個世界
And you will have moved on to an alternate universe.
一個糟透了的世界
A universe of shit.
你會被淹沒在那187A30B1里
You will be lost to civilization.
未誕生
And you will be unborn.
未成形
Unmade.
未存在
Undone.
所以 去掙些真正的體面吧 小伙子
So, go get some real decency, Son.
然後收拾好這堆爛攤子
And unfuck this mess.
36個小時
Thirty-six hours.
36小時
送快遞 你送快遞的！
Deliver. You deliver.
你就是個送快遞的！
That's what you do. You deliver, right?
對吧！
Right?!
你
You'll...
永遠
never...
不會知道
know...
我有多麼
Just how much...
多麼
I've...
愛
loved...
你
you...
你 永遠
You'll...
不會知道
Never know...
我有多麼
Just how much...
♫ 在乎你 ♫
I care...
♫ 就算我不告訴你 ♫
And if I tried
♫ 我也沒法掩飾我對你的深情 ♫
I still couldn't hide my love for you.
♫ 你得知道 ♫
You ought to know
♫ 我只是不告訴你 ♫
For haven't I told you so
♫ 你走了 把我的心也帶走了 ♫
You went away and my heart went with you
♫ 我為你禱告 ♫
I speak your name in my every prayer
♫ 我該怎麼向你證明  我有多麼愛你 ♫
If there is some other way to prove That I love you
我無法向你訴說
I swear I don't know how.
你不會明白的
You'll never know
你怎麼會明白
If you don't know now
艾麗莎
Elisa.
怎麼啦 寶貝？
What is it, my honey?
情況不妙啊
This isn't good.
我要把霍夫斯德勒博士喊來了
I'm going to call Dr. Hoffstetler
你今晚就得放走它了 寶貝
You got to release him tonight, honey.
我會回來幫你的
I'll come back and help you.
他要出來了
He's coming out.
呃
Ugh.
先生 恕我直言
Sir, If you don't mind me saying.
您看起來不太好啊
You don't look so well.
閉嘴
Shut up.
你聞到了嗎
Can you smell that?
是你的手指 都黑掉了
I think it's your fingers. They are black.
哦他來了 狗屁博士
There he is, Doctor fucking shitbird.
先生 你這說的太難聽了
There's no call for cursing, Sir.
給我滾出來 這車歸我了
Get out of the car. I'm taking it.
- 這是我的車 快他媽給我滾出去
- This is my car. - Get the fuck out.
- 這可是我的車 - 你聽不見我說話嘛？
- Out of my car? - Did I stutter?
真是傾盆大雨啊
今天沒有暗號嗎?
不要 不要 同志...
不要...
不要 求你了！
- 哎媽 幸好 斯特裏克蘭 - 你又講俄語了 鮑勃
- Strickland, thank God! - You were speaking Russian, Bob.
- 你叫什麼名字 - 霍夫斯德勒
- What's your name? - Hoffstetler.
哎呀 這時候就沒必要說假話了
Oh no. Don't lie. You don't need to.
你肚子上可是中了一槍
You took a bullet to your gut.
你離死不遠了
You're dead.
我要突擊隊裏所有人的名字 軍銜和藏身位置
I need the names, ranks and locations of the entire Strike Team.
突擊隊？
Strike Team?
搶走我們研究對象的那夥人
The ones that took the asset.
這個糖 雖然很便宜 但我從小就愛死它了
This candy. It's cheap candy. I love it ever since I was a kid.
有些人中意那些 看上去更高級的零食
Some folks favor more sophisticated snacks
牛軋糖和那些破玩意兒
Nougat center and all that fu-fu shit.
但我不喜歡
But not me, Bob.
我就愛吃這個
This is it for me.
我覺得緊張的時候
Now. Sometimes, if I'm feeling anxious
我就大嚼一番
I just bite right into it
但平時我還是會慢慢的
But mostly, I take my time.
將它一點一點吃完
I make it last.
他們的名字 編號和位置
Names, ranks and location of the strike team.
名字 編號！給我快點！
Names! Ranks! Now!
沒名字
No names
沒編號
No ranks
他們...
They...
早就逃之夭夭了
They just clean.
知道了布魯斯特 我會準備晚餐的
Alright Brewster. I'm gonna fix you dinner
然後我要出去一下 去幫個朋友做點事
and then I'm going to run out for a little while and help a friend.
- 做什麼事？- 就是幫朋友啦
- Help with what? - Helping a friend.
澤爾達
Zelda.
門
Door.
你他媽的連門都不能幫著開一下嗎
Well, You could well help me answer the door, Brewster!
你就坐在離門十尺的地方！
You're sittin' right there just ten feet away from it.
我背疼啊 婆娘 你去就是了
My back is acting up, woman. You move.
背疼 背疼 你就知道背疼
Your back. Your back. Always your back.
斯特裏克蘭先生！
Mr. Strickland!
你怎麼在這？
What are you doing here?
- 那個男人是誰？ - 它在哪？
- Who's that man, Zelda? - Where is it?
- 你在說啥？- 你把它帶到哪兒去了？
- What are you talking about? - Where did you take it?
澤爾達
Zelda.
在實驗室裏
The thing in the lab.
哪兒？
Where is it?
- 什麼在哪裏？- 給我坐下！
- Where is what? - Sit down!
哎呀先生我不是有意的
I'm sorry, Sir.
要是我知道 我肯定會告訴你的
If I knew anything I would surely tell you.
我還沒告訴你參孫的故事
That story about Samson.
是如何結束的
I never told you how it ended.
在非利士人狠狠折磨 還把他弄瞎了之後
After the Philistines torture him and blind him.
於是他向上帝祈求力量
Samson asks God for the strength he needs
就在最後一刻
And at the last minute, he is spared.
上天
And the Lord...
給予了他所要的力量
Gives him his strength back.
最後一次
One last time.
他抓住了神廟的柱子
And he holds the columns of the temple
然後用他有力的胳膊把柱子推了個粉碎
with his powerful arms and crushes them
整個廟都塌了 把非利士人也給埋了
And he brings the whole building down on the Philistines.
他是死了 但他也把那些狗屁玩意兒全部操翻了
He dies. But he gets every single one of those motherfuckers.
那就是他的願望
That is his will.
現在
Now.
你現在明白這個故事的意思了麼？
Do you know what that particular story means?
對於我們來說 黛利拉
For us, Delilah
它告訴我們 如果你有什麼瞞著我的話
It means that if you know something you're not telling me,
你終究會告訴我的
you're gonna tell me. Either.
無論是要等到我
Either before or after...
把你家毀掉之前
I bring this particular temple...
還是之後
down upon our heads.
那個啞巴把它從實驗室偷走了
Gal stole that thing right out the lab!
不管它是什麼
Whatever it is.
你去找吧
You go took it.
我聽我老婆
I heard my wife.
打電話的時候講的
Talking on the phone about it.
非常感謝你  富勒先生
Thank you very much, Mr. Fuller for your assistance.
- 你做了什麼? - 澤爾達!
- What have you done? - Zelda!
我得提醒他們! 他去找她了
I got to warn her. He's going after her
女人 你不許這樣做
You will do no such thing, Woman.
你管她做什麼? 她犯法了
Why you worry about her? She broke the laws
閉嘴  布魯斯特! 你閉嘴!
Shut up, Brewster! You shut up!
這麼多年你一言不發
For years, you don't talk
你可以繼續閉嘴了
and now you can't shut your mouth.
去你丫的 布魯斯特!
Damn you Brewster!
你不會明白的
You wouldn't understand.
說什麼都沒用 你永遠明白不了的
You couldn't understand. Not if you tried your whole life
- 嗨? - 吉爾斯 是你嗎?
- Hello? - Giles, that you?
- 是的 - 讓艾麗莎接電話
- Yes. - Put Elisa on the phone.
是澤爾達的電話
It's Zelda.
艾麗莎 親愛的 如果你能聽見我的話  弄點聲音
Elisa, honey, make a sound in the phone if you can hear
好
Okay, good.
他去找你了
He's coming for you.
你現在得走了 帶上那個東西
You got to go now and you go to take that thing with you.
怎麼了? 艾麗莎!
What? Elisa!
媽的
Dammit.
我們得下車了!
We have to go!
你在哪?
Where are you?
你他媽的到底在哪?!
Where the fuck are you?!
你好啊
That's nice.
你
和我
在一起
不 沒有我
沒有我
我從不會失手
I do not fail.
我做到了
I deliver.
艾麗莎!
Elisa!
不
No.
我的天
Fuck.
你確實是個神
You are a God.
關於她的故事
If I told you about it
我要怎麼說呢
What would I say?
說他們從此以後幸福的生活在一起?
That they lived happily ever after?
我相信是這樣的
I believe it is.
他們相愛
That they were in love
永遠相愛
That they remained in love.
我確定這是真的
I'm sure that's true.
當我想起她時 想起艾麗莎...
But when I think of her, Elisa...
只有一首詩 浮現在我的腦海
The only thing that comes to mind is a poem
那是幾百年前一對情侶的甜言蜜語...
Whispered by someone in love, hundreds of years ago...
「無法描述你的形狀」
「Unable to perceive the shape of You"
「我感覺到你圍繞著我」
"I find You all around me."
「因為你的存在 我滿眼都是你的愛意」
"Your presence fills my eyes with your love"
「它讓我的心變的柔軟」
"It humbles my heart"
「你無處不在」
"For you are everywhere"